Z Hespelt

> zhespelt.com
> z@zhespelt.com
> linkedin.com/in/zhespelt
> +1 762.233.2865

Full-stack Data Professional

Business Intelligence leader with more than a decade's worth of experience using data science and analytics to successfully drive action and positive outcomes. My, and my teams', work has been responsible for millions of dollars in revenue and reduced operational costs each year.

Experiences

Head of Data

Oct 2020 - Sep 2022 · 2 yrs SeedLegals.com

SeedLegals is the largest platform for startup funding and legals in the UK, with £1+ billion in funding raised and 35k+ companies and investors on platform.

- Reported to CEO and collaborated with C-level executives on big-picture projects (G-Suite, Slack)
- Worked internationally with stakeholders across the UK, Europe, APAC, and the Middle East
- Planned SL's data strategy and created short/long-term data roadmap
- Hired, trained, and managed SL's international, hybrid data team (BI & DS, FactorialHR)
- Built and administered SL's data warehouse (AWS, Postgres)
- Engineered SL's data infrastructure (Stitch, DBT, SQL, Python, Tableau, Metabase)
- Built high-dimensional behavioral data, enabling deeper insights, increasing sales & marketing effectiveness, and enabling the product team to better understand application usage
- Designed and MVP'd the Term-o-Meter (ToM), an application for analyzing and presenting deal-term data
- Advised startups on data-related product development and strategy

Sample of articles using my analyses:

- Narrative Violation: Women led startups you can get funding (SpiceStartups.com)
- Startup advisor shares: How much equity should you give your advisor? (SeedLegals.com)
- Startup equity: how much to give employees (SeedLegals.com)

Business Analyst III

Apr 2018 - Apr 2020 · 2 yrs 1 mo Rover.com

Rover is the world's largest network of 5-star pet sitters and dog walkers, with millions of completed bookings, hundreds of thousands of active service providers, and more data than you can shake a stick at.

- Supported Rover's Operations locally and internationally, including: CX, Booking Assurance, Trust & Safety, as well as the Data Science, Finance, and London satellite data teams
- Participated in hiring, training, and mentoring new data and business analysts
- Built most of Operations' analytical data structures, enabling greater understanding of Rover customers and more actionable KPIs
- Researched disintermediation and implemented workflow that saved ~\$500k/yr, reduced negative customer experiences, phishing messages, and account takeover incidents
- Engineered a disaster-relief pipeline that cut disaster response times from multiple days to a few hours and saved more than just operational costs
- Authored the data-literacy module of Rover's SQL 101 coursebook, and co-taught the
 5-week internal course

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

Sep 2013 - Oct 2017 · 4 yrs 2 mo Wizards of the Coast (Hasbro)

Wizards of the Coast—makers of Dungeons & Dragons, Magic: the Gathering, and a thousand other games—is a long-time titan in the card-game industry with decades' worth of data on player and customer behavior across video games, esports, retail business, and events.

- Developed player behavior models to forecast the impact program changes would have on player growth, retention, and lifetime revenue
- Reduced printing and shipping inefficiencies by accurately predicting major event attendance and product utilization
- Co-built the data warehouse and fraud detection algorithms used for the Magic: Duels video game, contributing to it being the most successful installment in the series
- Headed company-wide rollout of Tableau Server, bringing near-real-time insights to stakeholders
- Designed and built an esports commentary pipeline—cutting the roughly 3-week manual process to under 72 hours and dramatically improving its scope
- Researched and built valuable models for the legal team, aiding in favorable court rulings for Wizards and Hasbro

Data Analyst & Systems Administrator

Aug 2009 - Dec 2010 · 1 yr 5 mo Sound Transit

Sound Transit provides mass transit options to the Pacific NorthWest and—through their commitment to supporting small and disadvantaged businesses—are responsible for many millions of dollars going to female and minority-owned companies.

- Developed a system to acquire, analyze, and track gender and race equality data from 500+ companies, ensuring compliance with local and federal laws
- Visited construction sites regularly to inspect workforce data
- Designed and built EEO reporting, proving the effectiveness of the diversity program and resulting in the awarding of the Rosa Parks Award for outstanding commitment to equality—both regionally and nationally—in 2011

Education

BS: CIS

2007 - 2010 Cleveland State University

Bachelor of Science: Computer Information Systems Graduated with high honors.

Programming languages studied: Java, Python, R, Perl, Prolog, C#, SQL, Lisp as well as heavy use of JSON, XML, RegEx, Yaml and Markdown

AS: PSY

1997 - 1999 Seattle Central College

Associate of Science: Psychology (Focus on abnormal psychology)

Certifications

Computing for Data Analysis (94th percentile)

Johns Hopkins University Issued Oct 2012

Tableau Jedi

Tableau Issued Aug 2017